We go to the chainlink. GitHub again, we go to contracts. So C 0.8,
我们再一次来到 Chainlink 的 GitHub，前往 "/contracts/src/v0.8/"
actually have a mocks folder with VF coordinator v2 Mach dot Sol,
这里有一个 "mocks" 文件夹，里面有一个 "VRFCoordinatorV2Mock.sol"
and we're just going to use this as our mock.
我们就用它来作为我们的 "mock"
So in our contracts folder, we're gonna create a new file called test
所以在我们的 "contracts" 文件夹里，我们要创建一个新的文件，名为 "test"
（实际上应为创建一个新的文件夹，名为 "test"）
new file called V RF core, in a core, the two mock dot Sol,
再新建一个文件，名为 "VRFCoordinatorV2Mock.sol"
and we're just going to import this mock and have it be our mock.
然后我们直接导入这个 "Mock" 作为我们的 "mock"
So we'll do spdx.
我们先写下 `SPDX`
We'll do pragma, solidity, carrot zero, point 8.0, or seven or whatever we want to do,
再写下 `pragma solidity ^0.8.0`，或者是 7，或是任何我们想要版本
we'll do import at chainlink slash contracts slash SRC slash v 0.8. Slash, mocks, slash VRF. Pour did a tour B to mock that soul.
接着是 `import @chainlink/contracts/src/v0.8/mocks/VRFCoordinatorV2Mock.sol`
And we'll just check to see if it compiles with Hardhead compile,
我们用 hardhat 编译一下，看它是否能编译通过
and it looks like it's compiling as well. Awesome.
看起来编译过程一切正常，非常好
So now that we have our mock contract, we can actually go ahead and deploy it.
现在我们有了 "mock" 合约，就可以继续进行部署了
So we'll do a weight loi, the RF core de ne Tor V to Mach comma,
这里我们写 `await deploy("VRFCoordinatorV2Mock", )`
and then we'll give it our parameters in here.
然后在这里把我们的参数传递进去
We'll say from Deployer.
我们告诉它 `from: deployer`
Log is going to be true,
`log: true`
and then we're going to do our arguments.
接下来是我们的参数 `args`
Now, what are the arguments of this VRF coordinator, v2 Mk.
那么 "VRFCoordinatorV2Mock" 的参数是什么呢
Well, if we open the VRF coordinator v2 Mock, right in our VS code, or on GitHub,
如果我们在 VS Code 或者 GitHub 中打开 "VRFCoordinatorV2Mock"
we can actually see We will roll over to the constructor that it takes two things.
我们转到构造函数就能看到它接收两个东西
It takes a base fee and a gas price link.
这两个东西是 "baseFee" 以及 "gasPriceLink"
What are these
它们是什么呢？
first one? Well, the first one is this const base fee.
首先，第一个是 `const BASE_FEE`
If we go back to the documentation, we can see that there's this premium section of 0.25 Link rink B,
如果我们回到文档，就可以看到这里有一个 "Premium" 部分，内容是 "0.25 LINK"，Rinkeby 下
this means that for each request, there's a base fee of 0.25 link for every request.
这里的意思是对于每一次请求，它的基础费用是 0.25 LINK
So anytime we want to request a random number on Rinckey, it's going to cost us 0.25. Link,
所以无论何时，只要我们想在 Rinkeby 上请求一个随机数，它都会花费我们 0.25 LINK
or you can think of it as 0.25 Oracle gas to make this request.
或者你可以认为这次请求消耗了 0.25 的预言机 gas
So back in our deploy mocks, we can say base V equals,
回到我们的 "deploy-mocks" 我们可以说 `BASE_FEE =`
we could resemble Rinckey here and do 25, blah, blah, blah,
我们可以像 Rinkeby 一样，等于 `25` blah, blah, blah
or we could do ethers dot utils dot parse eath, of 0.25.
或者我们可以执行 `ethers.utils.parseEther(0.25)`
And I'll even put a little comment here, say 0.25 is the premium, it costs 0.25 Link per request.
我们在这里加一个注释， “0.25 是一个保底费用，每次请求花费 0.25 LINK”
And remember, the reason that this cost 0.25 Link per request versus the price feeds didn't cost anything
请记住，发出请求的成本是 0.25 个 LINK 而喂价不需要任何成本
is because the price feeds. If we look back at a chain that link,
这是因为，如果我们看一下 "data.chain.link"
each one of these price feeds is being sponsored by a group of protocols who are paying for all these requests already,
每一个喂价都有一组协议赞助，他们已经为这些请求支付了相应的费用
since there isn't a sponsor for this, we are the only ones requesting the randomness,
由于这里并没有赞助者，我们是唯一请求该随机数的人
we get to be the ones to actually sponsor getting this random number,
所以我们实际上就成为了获取该随机数的赞助人
then the second thing here is going to be the gas price link.
这里的第二个东西是 "gasPriceLink"
So let's create another const here to const. gas price link.
所以我们要再创建一个常量 `const GAS_PRICE_LINK`
But what this is, is actually a calculated value
但这究竟是什么呢？它实际上是一个计算值
is a calculated value based on the gas price of the chain.
它是一个基于所在链 gas 价格的计算值
Here's an example if we were to request a random number on Aetherium,
举个例子，如果我们是在以太坊上请求随机数
and the eath price skyrocketed up to like to like a billion dollars,
而以太坊的价格飙升至，比方说 10 亿美元
gas would be incredibly, incredibly expensive.
那么 gas 就会变得非常非常昂贵
Now when chain link nodes respond chain link nodes pay the gas fees, who give us randomness, and do external execution,
当 Chainlink 节点响应时，它会支付 gas 费以提供随机数并进行外部执行
the chain link nodes are actually the ones that pay the gas when returning randomness or executing an upkeep or etc.
也就是说在返回随机数以及执行 Upkeep 等操作时，实际上支付 gas 费的是 Chainlink 节点
If we go to our raffle dot soul, and scroll down to perform upkeep, or fulfill random words,
如果前往我们的 "Raffle.sol"，并且往下拉到 "performUpkeep" 或者 "fulfillRandomWords"
it's actually the chain link nodes that are calling these two functions and paying the gas for it,
实际上是 Chainlink 节点调用了这两个函数并为此支付了 gas
they get paid in Oracle gas to offset those costs.
它们需要被支付相应的预言机 gas 以抵消这些成本
But if the price of eath, or any native blockchain skyrocketed
但如果以太坊或是其它原生区块链代币的价格突然飙升
the chain that nodes itself to pay the gas fee.
Chainlink 节点就不得不自己支付这笔 gas 费了
So the chain link nodes have a calculated price have a calculated variable called the gas price per link,
所以 Chainlink 节点需要一个名为 "GAS_PRICE_LINK" 的计算量
which fluctuates based off the price of the actual chain, so that they never go bankrupt.
它会随着实际的链上价格进行波动，这样它们就不会破产了
Basically, the price of a request changes based off the price of gas for that blockchain,
大概意思就是，发起请求的价格会随着区块链的 gas 价格进行调整
you can kind of think of this as the link per gas, if you will,
你可以把它理解成，每 gas 对应的 link，如果你愿意的话
for now we can kind of just set it to whatever we want.
现在我们可以把它设置成任何我们想要的数值
And we'll just set it to one e nine,
我们就把它设置为 `1e9`
which is going to be equivalent to 1123456789.
它等于 "1" 后面有 9 个 0
So now that we have the base fee, and the gas price link,
现在我们有了 "BASE_FEE" 以及 "GAS_PRICE_LINK"
we'll grab this base fee, we'll have these be the arguments for our VR chord, enter V to mock,
我们获取这个 "BASE_FEE" 并把它们作为我们的 "VRFCoordinatorV2Mock" 的参数
so we'll say and actually we can delete that will say const, args equals base fee, and gas price link,
所以我们这么写，先把这里删掉，`const args = [BASE_FEE, GAS_PRICE_LINK]`
then we can take this args variable and just plop it in here.
然后获取这个 "args" 变量，并把它放到这里
Now we can do log mocks deployed,
现在我们就可以执行 `log("Mocks Deployed!")
then we can do log that a little line like this to let people know that this deploy script is done,
然后我们可以执行 `log()`，里面是很多这样的横线，好让人们知道这个部署脚本已经执行完成
then we'll just do a module that exports dot tags equals all and mocks.
接下来我们执行 `module.exports.tags = ["all", "mocks"]`
So now that we have a view of coordinator v2 Mock deployed,
现在我们有了一个完成部署的 "VRFCoordinatorV2Mock"
we'll come back over to our raffle and make some code around it.
我们再回到我们的 "Raffle" 并添加一些代码
Similar to what we just did with our deploy mocks.
就和我们在 "deploy-mocks" 中做的很像
We can say if development chains that includes network dot name, we'll do some stuff.
我们可以说 `if (developmentChains.includes(network.name))`，再执行某些操作
And we need to import development chains from our helper Hardhead config.
我们还需要从 "helper-hardhat-config" 中导入 "developmentChains"
And we need to import network from hard hat.
以及从 "hardhat" 中导入 "network"
My VS code automatically added them Wow, thanks VS code.
我的 VS Code 已经自动添加了它们，谢谢你 VS Code
Let's even just do const args and make this variable down here. Stick it in args.
甚至我们只需要在这里创建一个 `const args` 变量，再把它粘贴到这里
Our first argument is going to need to be this Vera fi to coordinator
我们的第一个参数是 "vrfCoordinator"
so let's make a variable we'll say let VRF core need torby to address
让我们来创建一个变量 `let vrfCoordinatorV2Address`
and if we're on a development chain, we're going to grab that mock contract.
如果我们是在开发链上，那我们还需要获取 "mock" 合约
So we'll say const PRF, Cor de ATAR V to mock equals await ethers dot get contract, the RF cord the cord to NATO Tor v two MK,
所以我们写 `const vrfCoordinatorV2Mock = await ehters.getContract("VRFCoordinatorV2Mock")`
and then we can set the RF coordinator v two address equals VRF core denater V two mach dot address.
然后我们就可以设置 `vrfCoordinatorV2Address = vrfCoordinatorV2Mock.address`